Killer looks.
American Psycho is a thriller, drama, crime film directed by Mary Harron.
A wealthy New York investment banking executive hides his alternate psychopathic ego from his
co-workers and friends as he escalates deeper into his illogical, gratuitous fantasies.
Patrick Bateman, played by Christian Bale.
Timothy Bryce, played by Justin Theroux.
Craig McDermott, played by Josh Lucas.
David Van Patten, played by Bill Sage.
Jean, played by Chloë Sevigny.
Evelyn Williams, played by Reese Witherspoon.
American Psycho is a 2000 black comedy horror film directed by Mary
Harron, who co-wrote the screenplay with Guinevere Turner.
Based on the 1991 novel by Bret Easton Ellis, it stars Christian Bale as Patrick Bateman, a
New York City investment banker who leads a double life as a serial killer.
Willem Dafoe, Jared Leto, Josh Lucas, Chloë Sevigny, Samantha Mathis, Cara Seymour,
Justin Theroux, and Reese Witherspoon appear in supporting roles.
The film blends psychological horror and black comedy to satirize 1980s
yuppie culture and consumerism, exemplified by Bateman.
Ellis considered his controversial novel unfilmable; however, producer Edward R.
Pressman was determined to adapt it and bought the film rights in 1992.
Stuart Gordon, David Cronenberg, and Rob Weiss considered directing the film
before Harron and Turner began writing the screenplay in 1996.
They sought to make a 1980s period film that emphasized the novel's satire.
The pre-production period was tumultuous; Harron chose Bale to play Bateman, but because distributor Lions Gate
Films sought Leonardo DiCaprio in the role, Harron was fired and replaced with Oliver Stone.
After DiCaprio and Stone left due to creative differences,
Harron was rehired and allowed to cast Bale.
Principal photography began in February 1999 in Toronto and New York City.
American Psycho premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 21, 2000,
and was released theatrically in the United States on April 14.
The film received mostly positive reviews, with praise for Bale's performance and
the screenplay, and grossed $34 million on a $7 million budget.
It has since developed a cult following and a strong
presence in meme culture since the 2010s.
A direct-to-video sequel, American Psycho 2, was released in 2002,
although it has little relation to the original.
By December 2024, a new adaptation of the novel,
directed by Luca Guadagnino, was in the works.
The film explores themes of new york city, based on novel or
book, businessman, psychopath, dark comedy.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.